好了
That's it.
能不能再让我欣赏一会儿
Can I just, you know,look at it for a minute?
你真是个艺术家 希德
You're an artist, Sid.
你是说 你就这么走了 然后我再也见不到这件艺术品了
You're telling me you're gonna walk outta here and I'm never gonna see it again?
很大的可能性 是的
There's a good chance of that, yes.
大多数人第一次 都会选择从小的图案纹起
Most guys, for the first one, they start with something small.
妈妈或是女朋友 的姓名缩写什么的
"Mom", girlfriend's initials,something like that.
而你却不同
Not you.
短短的两个月 就做了整整一套
You get a full set of sleeves all in a couple of months.
要是别人的话 可能要做好几年呢
It takes guys a few years to get the ink you got.
我可没那么多时间
I don't have a few years.
我也希望我有啊
Wish to hell I did.
把保险柜打开
The vault. Open it.
我们打不开 分行经理不在
We can't. The branch manager's not here.
他在哪儿
Where is he?
现在是午餐时间 他在白城堡
It's lunchtime. He's at White Castle.
什么白城堡
White Castle?
是个快餐店
A fast-food restaurant.
他们有那种小的方形汉堡
They serve those little square burgers.
我知道了
I know what it is.
别以为我在跟你闹着玩 快点儿
I'm not playing games. Open it.
先生 你包里已经有五十万现金了
Sir, you have half a million dollars cash in your bag.
你再考虑一下 如果
Don't you think it'd be better if...?
我们是警察 你已经被包围了
This is the police. You are completely surrounded.
把枪放下
Put down your weapon.
把枪放下 快点
Put down your weapons now!
在我所遇到的持枪抢劫案中从未见过被告完全不替自己辩护的
Rarely in the case of armed robbery do we hear a plea of no contest.
你真的不想辩护么 斯科菲尔德先生
Are you sure about this, Mr Scofield?
是的 法官大人
I'm sure, Your Honour.
法官大人 我请求休庭
Your Honour, we'd like to recess if we could.
我的当事人现在有些神志不清
My client's a bit confused at the moment.
-我很清醒   -法官大人 他不清醒
-I'm not.  -He is, Your Honour.
或许你应该听取一下你律师的提议
Perhaps you should heed her advice.
再用多一点的时间 去考虑你的回答
Take additional time to consider your response.
我考虑好了 法官大人
I've already done that, Your Honour.
我会在办公室决定如何判刑的
I'll retire to my chambers to determine sentencing.
现在休庭 下午一点半继续开庭
Court's recessed until 1:30.
我们走吧
Hey, come on. Let's go.
迈克叔叔
Uncle Mike?
我不想让你来
I didn't want you to come.
回家去吧 LJ.
Go home, LJ.
我不想让你看到我这样
I didn't want you to see this.
他一时肯定会接受不了的
He won't take this well.
这又能怪谁呢 他是你侄子
Can you blame him? He's your nephew.
他会认为任何与他有联系的人都会进监狱
He's beginning to think anybody he attaches himself to is gonna end up in prison.
并且他不是唯一一个这么认为的 迈克尔
And he's not the only one who's starting to feel that way, Michael.
能给我们一些时间吗
Will you give us a minute?
就一分钟
One minute.
你难道还不明白么
Don't you understand?
你完全放弃了你所有的权利
You just put the book in that woman's hand.
那个女法官会毫不留情地判你的刑
She's gonna lob it at you like a grenade.
审判和惩罚对她来说是一回事
Justice and punishment are the same thing to her.
我知道
I know.
告诉我你到底在想什么
then will you please tell me what's going through your head.
我们已经谈过了
We've been over this.
我一直都很了解你
I've known you all my life.
你根本不是一个有暴力倾向的人
You don't have a violent bone in your body.
况且你也不缺钱花
And I know you didn't need the money.
维罗妮卡
Veronica...
你为什么不让我来帮你呢
Why won't you let me help you?
你已经对我很好了 真的 你一向如此
You've been good to me my whole life.
但这次让我来处理此事 好吗
But you gotta let me deal with this. OK?
鉴于你没有前科 这次抢银行是初犯
Given your lack of prior criminal conduct
我很想给你减刑
I am inclined toward probation.
但是 事实证明你使用了有致命杀伤力的武器
However,the fact that you discharged a deadly weapon during the commission of the crime
说明你是蓄意犯罪
suggests malice to me.
以此为据
For that reason
我将判你入狱服刑 斯科菲尔德先生
I find it incumbent that you see the inside of a prison cell, Mr Scofield.
你提出想被关押在芝加哥
It says here that you've requested to be incarcerated
你家附近的监狱
somewhere near your home here in Chicago.
我很愿意这样做
I'm willing to honour that.
离那里最近的一级监狱
The closest level one facility to...
一级监狱?
Level one?
那可是戒备最森严的监狱 法官大人
That's maximum security. Your Honor.
辩护律师请不要打断我
I would ask counsel to refrain from interrupting me.
正如我所说
As I was saying
离那最近的一级监狱是 狐狸河 州立监狱
the closest level one facility would be Fox River State Penitentiary.
至于你的刑期 将会是五年
As for your sentence,I'm setting it at five years.
刑期满一半时可以申请假释
You'll be eligible for parole in half that time.
审判结果即刻生效
Sentence to be carried out immediately.
伊利诺伊州 芝加哥郊区 狐狸河州立监狱
都听好了 一个一个的进来接受检查
All right, people, step inside the door and check yourself for bugs.
听到敲门声就进来 随着队伍向前移动
When you hear the knock, step out. Keep the line moving.
我们不可能把一天的时间都浪费在你们身上
We ain't got all day to get this done.
排队的时候 不准出声
No more talking in line.
动作快点 你们还有不到5分钟的时间去洗澡
Move it. You got less than five minutes to take a shower.
都动起来 快点 快往前走
Keep that line moving.Keep it moving.Move it. Right now.
快点 抓紧时间
Let's go. Move, move.
下一位躺在板凳上 穿上衣服 快点走
Next down in the banks, dress. Let's go
姓名和号码
Name and bank number
斯科菲尔德・迈克尔 94941
Scofield Michael. 94941
你是教徒吗 斯科菲尔德
Are you a religious man, Scofield?
从来就没想过
Never thought about it
很好 十戒在这里一文不值
Good,cos the Ten Commandments don't mean a box of piss in here.
这里只有两戒
We got two commandments and two only.
第一条戒律是你在这里毫无希望可言
The first commandment is,you got nothin' comin'.
第二戒呢
What's the second commandment?
参考第一条戒律
See commandment number one.
明白了
Gotcha.
你说话绕弯子么
You talking out the side of your neck?
什么
Come again?
你想自作聪明吗
I said, are you bein' a smartass?
只想保持低调 不想引起注意 长官
Just trying to fly low, avoid the radar, boss.
等到刑满释放
Do my time and get out.
在我的地方谁也别想耍花样
There isn't any flyin' under my radar.
我了解了
Good to know.
嗨 长官 能不能找位兄弟上来装台空调
Hey,can a brother get some air conditioning up here,coach?
这里比吸毒妓女的热吻还要热
It's hotter than a crack ho's mouth,man.
让空调去见鬼吧 我要吸毒的妓女
To hell with the AC, man.Give me the crack ho.
快点
Come on!
你 小嫩鸡 看什么看
You, fish. What you lookin' at?
没事跑这里来干嘛
You look kinda pretty to be up in here, man.
小嫩鸡
Fish!
我建议你还是坐会吧 小嫩鸡
I suggest you take a seat, fish.
既然来了就好好服刑吧
Ain't nothing to do up in here but serve time.
没人会替你服刑的
Ain't nobody gonna serve it for you!
欢迎来到监狱乐园 小嫩鸡
Welcome to Prisneyland, fish.
你想谈一下吗
You wanna talk about it?
没有什么可谈的
It's not worth talking about.
要是让你一直睡不着觉的话 当然有的
If it's keeping you up, it is.
哦 只不过
No, it's just...
其实也没什么
It's nothing, you know.
是迈克尔的案子
Michael's case.
你已经尽力了
You did the best you could.
但他却没有
But he didn't.
他只想草草了事 没有任何争辩
He just sort of rolled over,he didn't put up a fight.
真的太不像他了
It's not like him. I...
对不起 我不应该提他的
I'm sorry. I shouldn't be talking about him.
嗨 这如果是你想的 就是你想的 不是吗
Hey, if it's on your mind, it's on your mind,right?
晚安
Good night.
所有狱警待命
All wings, guard coming out.
街头流氓 占据着篮球场
Trey Street Deuces got the hoops
北风 占据着看台
Nortenos got the bleachers.
森林小子 占据着举重器械
Woods got the weight pile
其他的地方由狱警掌管
The C.O.s got the rest.
我告诉你
I'm telling you,
狱警都是世界上最肮脏的流氓
the guards are the dirtiest gang in this whole place.
他们与我们唯一的不同
The only difference between us and them
就是他们有徽章
is the badge.
抱着宠物的那个人是谁
Who's the pet lover?
他一直不肯承认 他是 D.B. 库珀
He'll deny it, but he's DB Cooper.
三十年前带着一百五十万现金从一架飞机空降
Parachuted out of a plane 30 years ago with a million and a half in cash.
看起来不像啊
Doesn't look like the type.
谁看起来像呢
Who does?
嗨! 怎么样 百货商店 你还好吗
Hey! What up, Wholesale? You OK?
非常不错
Gonna be greater later.
是呀
Yeah.
你怎么和小嫩鸡混在一起了 伙计
What you doin' with this fish, man?
他是我的新室友
He's my new cellie.
他和贩卖部的人很熟
Wholesale's got it wired up out of commissary
任何你想要的 他都能给你弄到
Anything you want, he can get it for you.
你再把我的事抖出来
You keep handin' out my jacket
我就给你好看
I swear I'm gonna bust your grape.
你有这本事么
Man,you couldn't bust a grape in Napa with a set of cleats on.
你再说些什么 朋友 你想找麻烦是么
What are you talkin'about? Man, you want to bump your gums.
不 不 不 一直都是你在说
Oh, no, no. Now you're talking, talking, talking...
我想找个人
I'm looking for someone.
他叫林肯・布伦斯
Guy named Lincoln Burrows
水缸 林克
Linc the Sink?
他们现在这么叫他么
That what they're calling him now?
没错
Yeah.
他要是想找你麻烦 你可就死定了 小白脸
As in,he'll come at you with everything but the kitchen, snowflake.
在哪儿能找到他
Where can I find him?
这人谋杀了副总统的哥哥
Man killed the VP's brother.
一个月后 他就要坐电椅了
and in a month he's getting the chair.
这里没人比他更危险了
Which means no one up this river is more dangerous than him
谁能把他怎样 杀他两次么
What are they gonna do, kill him twice?
有没有办法让我接近他
There a way I can get to him?
不太可能 他们只有在做礼拜和P.I.的时候才出来
oh,no,The only time those boys get out is for chapel and P.I.
-P.I.是什么   -监狱工厂
-PI? What's that?   -Prison industry.
他们都要去干活
The guys that get along, get to work
刷油漆 刮刮墙 还有做床垫
you know,painting,scrapping,making mattresses, you name it.
小嫩鸡 如果我是你的话 才不会感到兴奋
I wouldn't get excited if I were you, fish.
你连监狱工厂的味都闻不着
You ain't sniffin' none of P.I.
为什么
Why's that?
因为工厂由约翰・阿布鲁奇掌控
Cos John Abruzzi runs it.
约翰・阿布鲁奇 约翰・阿布鲁奇
John Abruzzi,John Abruzzi?
约翰.阿布鲁奇 约翰.阿布鲁奇
John Abruzzi John Abruzzi
你为什么这么想见布伦斯
Why do you want to see Burrows so bad anyhow?
因为他是我哥哥
Because he's my brother.
-他们驳回了上诉  -那就再上诉
-They denied the motion.   -Then do it again.
不行 就这样了
I can't. That's it.
五月十一日就是那天
May 11th. That's the date, man.
就是我被执行死刑的日子
That's the date they, uh, you know...execute me.
我知道
I know.
迈克尔 那人不是我杀的
I didn't kill that man, Michael.
可他们有证据
The evidence says you did.
我才不管什么证据 反正我没杀人
I don't care what the evidence says. I didn't kill him.
向我发誓
Swear to me.
我向你发誓 迈克尔
I swear to you, Michael.
那么 他们 怎么会搞错呢
But how did they get it wrong, then?
法庭 上诉
The courts, the appeals...
不知道 我也不知道
Don't know. Don't know.
现在回想起来 我是被陷害的
I keep thinking, looking back on it,is I was set up.
不管是谁要陷害我
And whoever it was that set me up
都想把我尽快至于死地
wants me in the ground as quickly as possible.
表达爱意 还有其他什么词儿呢?
What's another word for "love"?
什么情况下说的
What's the context?
哦  就好像
Oh, you know.
我很爱你
The "I love you so much
再也不去酒馆胡闹 之类的
I ain't never knockin' over a liquor store again" context.
还有 不用太华丽
Except, you know, classy.
嗯
Mm.
我就是想向女朋友求婚
I'm proposing to my girl, if you gotta know.
在信里
In a letter?
你有更好的方法
You got a better way?
当面说效果会更好
Face to face works pretty good.
这可不是什么浪漫之地
This place ain't exactly the romantic spot.
我要让她乘着史泰登岛渡轮
I'm gonna have her go get on the Staten Island Ferry
然后当她看到了帝国大厦
then once she can see the Empire State Building
这时她打开信
she opens the letter...
我就差不多成功了
It's like almost being there
但事实上 我根本做不到这一切
Except for the fact that I won't be there.
用 爱恋 试试
Try "passion".
哦 哦 爱恋 爱恋 这个词好 爱恋
Ooh! Ooh! "Passion. Passion" That's dope. Passion
怎么拼的 p-a-s-h
How do you spell that? Is it P-A-S-H...?
没有 h
No H?
LJ 等一下 等一下
LJ, hold up. Hold up?
我想 我办不到
I don't think I can go through with this.
不会有事的 相信我
Everything's gonna be fine. Trust me.
-我们彼此了解 对吧   -是的
-We understand each other,then?  -yeah
是星期五 不是星期六 也不是星期日 是星期五
Friday. Not Saturday, not Sunday. Friday.
完全明白
Totally understood.
面额是百元 五元 还有一元的 都不要
I don't want 100s,I don't want fives, I don't want ones.
明白 明白
I know, I know.
只要十元和二十元的
Tens and 20s only.
开始行动
It's on.
警察
Police!
阿布鲁奇  我想让你雇我去监狱工厂
Abruzzi. I need you to hire me at P.I.
爬开
Beat it.
或许你该听听我要说的
Maybe you oughta hear what I gotta say.
你没有我要的东西
You got nothing I need.
我可不这么认为
Wouldn't be too sure of that.
是我错了
My mistake.
我想要的就是一只鸭子
Just what I need. A duck.
监狱工厂  阿布鲁奇
a P.I, Abruzzi.
说不定我能帮上你大忙呢
You might find I can be of more assistance than you think.
再考虑一下
Mull it over.
想好了就来找我谈
Come find me when you're ready to talk.
伙计们 都利索点
All right, guys. Pick it up.
我今晚还想回家呢!
I wanna get home tonight.
马齐奥
Maggio?
说吧 什么事
Yeah. So?
就是这个狗样娘的家伙指证阿布鲁奇的
That's the son of a bitch at fingered Abruzzi.
菲波纳奇
That's Fibonacci?
还以这个混蛋会永远消失呢
I thought that punk was gone forever.
很明显  有人找到了他
Evidently somebody found him.
看来有人想和我们玩游戏
somebody messin' with us?
这个你肯定不信
This you're not gonna believe.
这是什么
What is it?
纹身看上去像新的
Tattoo looks fresh.
按住
Hold that.
看来糖尿病患者 还真不介意打针
I guess being a diabetic,you don't mind needles.
我叫迈克尔
I'm Michael, by the way.
斯科菲尔德 我看了你的资料
Scofield. I read your report.
那么你是
And you are?
叫我 唐克雷蒂 医生就行
Dr. Tancredi will do.
和州长同姓唐克雷蒂?
"Tancredi" like the governor?
你们不会是亲戚吧
You're not related, are you?
真想不到州长的女儿会在监狱里工作
Wouldn't think you'd find the daughter of Frontier Justice Frank working in a prison.
而且还是 医生
As a doctor, no less.
我喜欢解决问题 而不是制造问题
I believe in being part of the solution,not the problem.Hm.
通过改变自身来适应万变的世界
"Be the change you want to see in the world."
怎么了
What?
没什么 只不过这是我的座右铭
Nothing. That was just my senior quote.
原来是你说的
That was you?
我一直认为是甘地说的
This whole time I was thinking it was Gandhi.
你很有意思
You're very funny.
坐好了
Sit tight.
手按住 我马上回来
Put direct pressure on that. I'll be back in a sec.
那么 我们怎么来治疗呢
So, how do we play this?
你给我开几个星期的药吧
You hook me up with a few weeks' supply?
想的美
Nice try.
这里不允许有瘾君子的
No hypos on the floor.
我是不会吸毒的 相信我
I'm the farthest thing from a junkie.Trust me.
我告诉你  迈克尔
I got news for you,Michael.
信任这东西 在监狱里一钱不值
"Trust me" means absolutely zero inside those walls.
你接受胰岛素的途径 就是必须经由我允许
The only way you're getting that insulin is if I'm administering it.
以后我们还会见面的 是么
Guess we'll be seeing a lot of each other,then,huh?
我想是的
I guess so.
布伦斯 的死刑一切就绪了
We're all clear on the Burrows execution
很好
Good
还有件事
Except for one thing
马克莫拉主教不同意这么做
Bishop McMorrow is not in the fold.
他和州长关系不错
He's got a lot of influence with the governor.
他们以前是校友
They went to prep school together apparently.
时间越近
Look, the closer it gets,
我就越担心
the more I'm worried that the bottom
总怕会出什么乱子
is gonna fall out of this whole thing.
去安排我和主教大人见一次面
Well, maybe it's time you arranged a visit with the good bishop, then.
记住 再有一个月
Look, in one month
一切都会结束
it'll all be over.
人子必须被交在罪人手里(选自圣经 路加福音 第24章)
"The Son of Man must be delivered into the hands of sinful men
被钉在十字架上
and be crucified,
第三日复活
and the third day rise again."
他们记住了他的话 你们也应该那样做
And they remembered his words. And so should you.
今天就到这里吧 愿上帝与你们同在
Good day, gentlemen. May God be with you.
迈克尔
Michael?
这是怎么回事
Why?
我要把你弄出去
I'm getting you out of here.
布伦斯 快点 快乐时光结束了
Burrows! Roll it up. Happy hour's over.
根本不可能
It's impossible.
除非监狱是你自己设计的
Not if you designed the place it isn't.
太正式了
Too formal.
太贺卡样了
Too greeting-card.
这事迟早要决定的
We gotta make a decision sooner or later, you know.
还有时间的啊
We have time.
实际上 没有了
We don't, actually.
有些时候 事情还是抓紧点的好
I mean, at some point, we gotta pull the trigger on this thing.
我不想这么草率
I don't wanna rush this.
人生只有一次 我不想出任何差错
We're only gonna do it once. We have to get it right.
亲爱的 能问你个问题么
Honey, can I ask you something?
当然了
Of course.
你是不是要把(婚礼)推迟
Are you putting this off?
你说什么啊
What do you mean?
我是说你是不是改变主意了
I mean, are you having second thoughts?
不 亲爱的 从来没有
No. Honey,no
我没有
I'm not.
我也不知道
I don't know.
只是我禁不住不去想它
I just can't help thinking this is about...
不是这样的
It's not.
我爱你
I love you.
我要成为你的妻子
And I wanna be your wife.
爱恋 你是怎么想的阿
"Passion"? What were you thinking?
你自己也同意的
Hey, you went for it.
她很可能认为我在这里变得娘娘腔了
She probably thinks I went sissy up in here.
爱恋 多了一个字 话就变罗索了
"Passion".Got more than one syllable, too much talking.
从现在开始
That's me from now on.
以后只用单音节的词
One-Syllable Sucre.
是 否 爱 恨 爱
"Yes","no","love","hate"..."love".
-不要着急  -你开什么玩笑
-Give it time.  - Are you kidding?
我在向她求婚
I proposed to her
又不需要太多的时间 是 还是 不 一个字而已
That doesn't take time.Si or no. One syllable,man.
她都是周二来探监的
She's supposed to come around for a conjugal on Tuesday.
来之前她总是先打个电话的
She's always calling me beforehand,letting me know she's coming.
可是这次 音信全无
This time, man, I ain't heard a peep.
是你把她吓跑了
You spooked her.
斯科菲尔德快起来 典狱长要见你
Scofield. Get it together. Pope wants to see you.
这可不妙 小嫩鸡
No good, fish.
从未有人见过典狱长
No one gets an audience with the Pope.
除非他对你的所作所为感兴趣
Not unless he's real interested in what you got going on.
芝加哥大学的高才生
Top of your class at Loyola.
还成绩优秀
Magna cum laude, in fact.
真不敢想象像你这么有资历的人
I can't help wondering what someone with your credentials
竟然会来到这种地方
is doing in a place like this.
我想可能是几个月前走错路了
Took a wrong turn a few months back, I guess.
听你说起来就像是交通违规一样
You make it sound like a traffic infraction,
蹲监狱与单行道上逆向行车 是两码事
Like all you did was turn the wrong way up a one-way street.
谁都有犯错误的时候
Everyone turns up one sooner or later.
我叫你来的原因是
The reason I called you here,
我看了你的档案 在职业一栏里
I noticed in your l-file, under "Occupation",
你写的 无业
you put down "unemployed".
那不是真的 对么
That's not true, now,is it?
斯科菲尔德 我知道你是个结构学工程师
I know you're a structural engineer, Scofield.
沙伽罕建造了泰姬陵
Shah Jahan built the Taj Mahal
以此来表达他对妻子爱的永恒
as a monument to his undying love for his wife.
我老婆很喜欢这个故事
My wife is quite fond of the story.
她认为非常浪漫
It appeals to the romantic in her.
嫁给了一个像我这样工作的人
Being married to someone in corrections,
是一件恐怖的事
terrible job.
谁会愿意呢
Wouldn't wish it on anyone.
但在这三十九年里我老婆从没有抱怨过
And yet, in 39 years, my wife has never complained.
更遗憾的是 我从未感谢过她
And the worst part of it is,I've never thanked her.
因为我说不出口
So, because I couldn't say it,
我想做一个
I thought, you know, I could build it.
这个六月就是我们结婚40周年纪念日
Come June, it's our 40th anniversary.
但是这里  你看
But here, look...
你看  问题是
You see, the problem is,
我造得越多
I build anymore,
它就会像空中楼阁一样塌下来
it's all gonna come down like a house of cards.
我想你能帮助我一下
That's where I was hoping you could be of assistance.
作为回报 你每周可以在这里工作三天
for the favour,I can offer you three days of work a week in here
也就不必去什么操场了
and it'll keep you off the yard.
我做不了
I can't do it.
孩子 我敢肯定 在这里让我欠你人情要比你欠我的好
Son,it's better for me to owe you one in here than it is for you to owe me one,
我会考虑的
I'll take my chances.
咱们没什么好谈的了
Then we're through here.
警卫
Guard!
两磅的大麻
Two pounds of pot?
你想干什么  留下案底么
What were you trying to do, set a record?
一点都不好笑 LJ 你很可能会进监狱的
It's not funny, LJ. You could be going to jail.
看来需要人来好好教教你
It's pretty obvious to me you need some guidance.
嗨
Hey.
谢谢
Thanks.
找谁来合适呢 沃布客斯 老爸吗
From who? Old Daddy Warbucks?
给他个机会 他是一个好人
Give him a chance. He's a good man.
我们没有共同语言
We got nothing in common.
你到底是怎么了 LJ
Where's this coming from, LJ?
上学期你几乎全是A 可现在
Last semester you were getting almost all As, and now...
是你父亲 对不
It's your father, isn't it?
我没有父亲
I don't have a father.
你这么做可不明智 相信我
It wasn't an immaculate conception, honey. Trust me.
也许你应该去看看他了
Maybe it's time you went and saw him.
妈妈
Mom
Mom.
不要
Don't.
我也想让你有个美好的未来
I'm about as excited by the prospect as you are,
但是有些东西是必需要放弃的
but something's gotta give
你再这样下去会毁了自己前程的
You have got too much potential to be screwing up your life like this.
如果他们把你送到 泰勒维尔 或是 马里昂 怎么办
What if they'd sent you to Taylorville or Marion and not here?
我想我也会这么做的
I think I'd be doing the same thing I'm doing in here,
吃吃果冻 喝喝饮料
eating Jell-O,drinking Kool-Aid.
我知道你要干什么
I know what you're doing.
你和林肯被关到一起绝非巧合
It's not luck of the draw that you're in here with Lincoln.
你忘了我非常了解你们俩
You forget I know you. Both of you
你们兄弟之间的感情 恐怕是我见过的最特别的了
You two have the most dysfunctional idea of love I've ever seen.
他为了不让你在街头胡闹而打你
What,he beats you up to keep you off the street,
现在你又主动和他关在一起
so you get yourself tossed into Fox River with him?
为了什么
To what?
救他
Save him?
你应该告诉我 我曾像你一样的爱他
I deserve to know. I loved him as much as you did.
你的爱已成往事 而我的却不是
Past tense for you, maybe. Not me.
我大学毕业后曾给过他机会
I gave him a shot when I got back from college. I did.
即使在那种情况下
Even with all the stuff that was going on with him,
我还是尽我所能的帮助他 他却不把这些当回事
I did all I could to make it work, and he threw it away.
你是否曾想过在你离开他的时候 他非常的伤心
You ever think maybe he was hurt that you left in the first place?
不要这样做
Don't do this.
无论你想做什么 不要做
Whatever it is you're doing,don't do it.
会有更好的办法的 我已经提出上诉了
there's a better way.I'm already appealing your case.
我告诉过你不要再管这件事了
I told you to leave alone
我已经和林肯所在地区的主教取得了联系上了
I've gotten in touch with the diocese about Linc.The bishop...
没用的 只能延缓一下时间而已
That won't stop it. It'll only delay it.
你真想帮忙么
You wanna do something?
找出是谁要至他于死地
You find out who's trying to bury him.
没有人要至他于死地
Nobody's trying to bury him.
证据确凿
The evidence was there.
证据是伪造的
The evidence was cooked.
探监时间结束了
Visiting hours are now over.
照顾好自己
Take care of yourself.
有人要他死 维罗妮卡
Someone wants him dead, Veronica.
有太多的阴谋
Something more is going on here.
这是在绝望 迈克尔 你是在否定事实 面对现实吧
This is desperation,Michael.You're grabbing at straws.You're in denial.
或许是吧 我不能看着他死 我做不到
Maybe. But I can't watch him die.I won't do that.
先生们
Gentlemen.
布伦斯的事 我能帮上什么忙
What is it about the Burrows situation that I can help you with?
我们认为你对州长有着很大的影响力
It's our understanding that you have great influence with the governor.
我不会说是 非常大 或是什么 影响力
I wouldn't say it's great, or influence.
我们是朋友
We're friends.
我们知道 您反对死刑
It's also our understanding that you oppose the death penalty.
我是上帝的子民 当然会这么认为了
I'm a man of God. How could I not?
在这个案子里 我们希望您能改变一下立场
In this case,we're hoping you'll suspend that position
至少是暂时的
at least temporarily.
如果囚犯需要我的干涉
If the inmate appeals to me for intervention,
我怎么能坐视不管呢
how can I turn my back on him?
我很欣赏 您用问题来回答问题
You have a habit of answering a question with a question.
你的方式好像是 用问题来问更多的问题
And you have a way of asking questions that beg more questions.
这么说来您是不同意了
Are you saying you won't do it?
我的话已经够明确的了
I'm not a man to equivocate.
您
You're what,
现在已经62岁了
62 years old now, Your Excellency?
没错
That's right.
那么 我想
I would assume, then,
您应该很清楚政府的税收政策吧
that you should be well-versed in how our government's tax system works.
在教会掩护下中饱私囊
Taking personal capital gains under the church's tax shelter,
难道阁下不认为这是一种欺骗么
well,that would be fraud, wouldn't it, Your Excellency?
我是不会因为恐惧 而放弃自己的信念的
I will not be cowed into forsaking my beliefs.
你吓不倒我 谁也做不到
Not by you, or anyone else.
佩服
Admirable.
再见
Good day, Excellency.
凯勒曼 先生
Mr Kellerman
情报局为什么对这个案件如此感兴趣
what is it about this case that the Secret Service is so interested in?
那人杀了副总统的哥哥
The man killed the Vice-President's brother.
-他说什么  -你听我说
-What did you say?  -You heard me.
有人找到了菲波纳奇
Someone found Fibonacci.
我正看着这张照片呢
I'm looking at the photos right now.
狗娘养的留了胡子 还戴着太阳镜
Son of a bitch has got a beard,sunglasses.
一看就是 证人保护计划
Witness protection if I ever saw it.
谁提供的消息
Who was this someone?
信封上面没有回信地址
There's no return address on the envelope.
只有一个纸做的小鸟
Just...this folded-up bird
折纸么
made of paper.
没错 就是
Like origami.
对 是的
Yeah,like that,like origami.
你是 查尔斯・韦斯特莫兰德 对吗
You're Charles Westmoreland, right?
咱们认识么
Do I know you?
我在你老婆逝世前曾认识她
I knew your wife, before she passed.
-你认识 玛拉   -你说得是 安妮
-You knew Marla?   -You mean Ann?
你是怎么认识她的
How'd you know her?
我们在波士顿有过谈话
We taught together in Boston.
-东法明敦吗   -你是说 西威灵顿 吗
-East Farmington.   -You mean West Wilmington?
别再考我了
No more tests
我保证
I promise.
你好像知道我的一切
Seems you know everything about me.
-你是谁  -迈克尔・斯科菲尔德
-Who are you?  -Michael Scofield.
你是怎么把它带进来的
How'd you get it in here?
首先  她不是它
First off, she's not an it.
她是 玛尔林
She's Marilyn
自从监狱允许囚犯带宠物
and she's grandfathered back from the days
她就被带进来了
when prisoners were allowed a creature comfort or two.
我听说你是 D.B. 库珀
I heard you were DB Cooper.
一旦有新人来到这里
Every new fish comes in here
总能听到
first thing they hear
查尔斯・韦斯特莫兰德 是 D.B.库珀
is that Charles Westmoreland is DB Cooper.
我会像告诉他们一样的告诉你
I'll tell you like I tell them.
你想听 库珀 的故事么
You want the Cooper story?
我什么也告诉不了你 因为我不是他
I can't give it to you, cos I'm not him.
真可惜
It's too bad.
真希望 是真的 一个传奇式的人物
sort of wish it was true. The man's a legend.
没有人比我还想了 朋友
Nowhere near as much as I wish it were true, friend.
那样我就会在外面有一百五十万了
I'd have a million five waiting for me on the outside.
如果我是你的话我会小心点
I'd put some grass under'em if I were you.
如果你雇我的话 一切都会变得简单
This thing'd go a whole lot easier if you'd just hire me.
你到底想怎样
What is this all about?
如果有人能把你弄出这里的高墙去
Say you were able to get outside those walls.
你能不能找人帮他销声匿迹
would you have the people in place to make you disappeared forever?
-你问这个干嘛  -只是出于好奇
-What do you care?  -I'm just curious.
菲波纳奇在哪儿
Where's Fibonacci?
这不是解决事情的方法
That's not the way it works.
他们要是敢动我 约翰
They come at me, John
我不会放过你的
I'm coming after you.
我还真不信
I doubt it.
好吧
All right.
我完全把你看错了 斯科菲尔德
I totally misjudged you, Scofield.
我认为你不是一个惹事生非的人
I didn't think you were the agitating type.
像那样的事情在我的监狱里是不允许的
Behaviour like that will not be tolerated in my prison.
九十天的禁闭
90 days in the SHU
足够让你想清楚的了
That ought to be enough time to convince you of that fact.
九十天
90 days?
没错
That's right.
你还想说什么
Something you wanna say?
只是...
It's just...
要是在禁闭房里我就不能帮你了
I'm not of much value to you in the SHU.
帮我
Value?
恩 泰姬陵
Hm- mm... the Taj.
要是由于承重压力分布不均
It'd be a shame for the 8th wonder of the modern
而使世界第八大奇迹倒塌可就太可惜了
world to collapse 'cause the stress's improperly propagated
重力什么分布不均?
Improperly propagated?
承重压力分布不均
Improperly propagated
结合处超过了承重极限
The joints are overloaded.
从而不能再提供任何的承载力
They won't provide anywhere near the sheer strength
以承受整个建筑物的荷载了
the completed structure will need.
需要花费多长的时间
How much work are we talking?
你是想在6月完成吧
You want it by when, June?
是的
Yes.
那么现在就该开工了 你说呢
Then we'd better get started,wouldn't you say?
谁啊
Who's there?
马克莫拉主教昨晚被杀了
Bishop McMorrow was killed last night.
在他睡觉的时候 被人枪杀了
Someone shot him while he was sleeping.
我想 你可能想知道
I thought you'd wanna know.
谢谢
Thanks.
迈克尔 是对的
Michael was right.
水缸 有人来探监
Sink! You got a visitor.
他被捕了
He was arrested.
为什么
For what?
携带大麻
Possession of marijuana.
我认为你应该以父亲的身份给他些建议 在你...
I figured he could use some fatherly advice before it's...
在被 处决 之前
Gone forever?
我没那个意思
I didn't mean that.
我知道 谢谢你 莉莎
I know you didn't. Thanks, Lisa.
坐吧
Sit down.
大麻是么
Dope, huh?
吸食还是贩卖
Using or dealing?
有区别么
What's the difference?
你想干什么
Then what? you, uh,
想混出名气么
think it gives you some kind of street cred?
你有美好的前程 要好好珍惜
You got a piece of the good life. Take advantage.
好的 我明白了
Look, I get it.
你们那一套
The whole thing.
她把我拉到这儿
She drags me in here
你给我讲大道理 走的时候会焕然一新
you give me a big speech,I walk away a changed man.
科科都拿 A
Straight "A"s
哈佛 长大后成为一名牙医
Harvard, grow up and be a dentist.
总比待在这里好
It's better than being here.
你要明白 受惩罚的是你自己
You gotta realise who's getting punished
你做的那些事
when you're doing the things you're doing.
别以为受惩罚的是我 那会是你自己
You think it's me. It's you.
我过去也曾这样过
I did the same thing.
因为一个老人的离开而去责怪他
Punished the old man cos he was gone.
而我又得到了什么呢
Look where it got me.
我不是在求 你爱我
I'm not asking you to love me.
很久以前我就失去这个机会了
I already screwed up that chance long ago
我希望你能自爱
I'm asking you to love yourself.
现在后悔还来得及
You can still put the brakes on this thing.
那么  这就是所谓的父亲的建议
So that's what fatherly advice is like.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
我有作业要写
I got homework.
他们想让我死 LJ
They're putting me to death, LJ.
再有一个月 我就死了 你明白吗
In a month's time, I'll be dead. You get that?
对我来说 你早就死了
You're already dead to me
不是吧
Oh,no.
是
Yes.
什么 你是说是 好的
What, you mean "yes, yes"?
是 是
Yes! Yes!
好的
Yeah!
哦  只有一件事
Oh, there's just one thing.
没问题
Of course.
我妈妈说要等你出来
My mom say we gotta wait till you get out.
当然 宝贝儿
Of course,Miamor
她想在教堂里举行婚礼
She wants it to be in in a church.
这些都不成问题
Okay. Estabien
天主教堂
A Catholic church.
我们不会破坏天主教的规矩的 对么
Wouldn't want to mess with the Catholic roots, would we?
你在罗约尔学院读过书啊 (芝加哥大学)
You went to Loyola.
你在背后调查我
You've been checking up on me.
我喜欢了解我的病人
I like to get to know my patients.
我去过西北大学 比你晚两年毕业
I went to Northwestern.Graduated two years after you did.
或许我们以前见过 喝醉了 或是在酒吧外面的某个地方
Maybe we met before.you know,drunk,out at a bar or somewhere.
我不记得了
I would have remembered.
-是在夸我么  -不是
-That a compliment?   -No.
怎么了
What?
你的血糖含量 每0.1公升只有50毫克
Your blood glucose is 50mg per decilitre.
怎么了
So?
说明你低血糖
It's hypoglycaemic.
你的身体对胰岛素的反应 不像是一个糖尿病患者的
Your body's reacting to the insulin like you're not a diabetic.
你肯定你患有一型糖尿病吗
You sure it's type 1 diabetes you've got?
从小就是
Ever since I was a kid.
好吧
All right
有没有感到局部痉挛或者出冷汗
You're not experiencing any tingling sensation,cold sweats or...
医务室
Infirmary.
是的
Yes.
是的 我做了
Yeah, he did.
不  我一定要做 我需要他们
No, I did and I do, I need them
好的 太好了 午饭后我会打给他的
OK,Great. Well, I'll call him after lunch, then.
多谢了 我这里还有病人 好吗
Thanks. I'm with a patient. OK.
我想你再来的时候 给你做些检查
I'd like to run some tests next time you're in.
我不想给一个并不需要胰岛素的人注射胰岛素
I don't want to administer insulin to a man who doesn't need it.
好的 没问题
Yeah. Sure.
好的
OK.
你是怎么来的
How'd you get here, by the way?
哦  你知道的
Oh, you know.
我要知道就不问你了
I don't. That's why I asked.
-你认识的 是海克特   -什么
-You know... Hector.  -What?!
我没钱坐公车 只好搭他的车来了
I didn't have any money for the bus, so he offered me a ride.
他人挺好的
He was really sweet.
亲爱的  他只是一个朋友
Honey, he's just a friend.
不  不止是朋友
No, he's not "just a friend."
我了解 海克特 我了解男人
I know Hector. I know men.
男人和女人不可能成为朋友
Men and women can't be friends
一个男人带着一个女孩 穿过州边五百英里
A guy doesn't drive a girl 500 miles across state lines
就因为他想交朋友
because he wants to be friends.
多情种子 抓紧时间
Casanova! Wrap it up.
嗨 不要再胡思乱想了好吗
Hey. You got nothing to worry about, OK?
我要嫁的人是你
It's you I'm marrying.
我担心的不是你
It's not you I'm worried about.
再有十六个月
Sixteen more months.
我爱你
I love you.
别紧张伙计 好吗
Be easy, son, all right?
苏克雷告诉我你是这里的药店
Sucre tells me you're the local pharmacy.
你想要什么 伙计
What do you need, man?
富格那克
Fugnac.
我只说英语  小白脸
I only speak English, white boy
是一种抵制胰岛素药效的药
It's an insulin blocker.
一种非处方药 任何药店都能买到
Standard over the counter variety.You can get it at any pharmacy.
那么你可以去药房拿
You can get that at Medical, then.
我办不到
I can't get it at medical.
为什么
Why not?
因为他们已经给我注射了胰岛素
Because they're giving me insulin shots.
你还真能整 你知道嘛
You're one mixed-up cracker.you know that?
你到底能不能帮我
Can you get it for me or not?
除非你告诉我为什么那么想去医务室
Only if you tell me why it's that you keep goin back up to
注射那本不需要的胰岛素
Medical to get an insulin shot for which you don't need.
我喜欢那里的环境
I like the ambience.
哈哈
Uh- huh.
这么说答应了
We in business?
斯科菲尔德 我不知道你有什么本事
Scofield! I don't know what you did
但是阿布鲁奇让我把这张监狱工厂的卡给你
but Abruzzi wanted me to give you this P.I. card.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
从无业游民成功升级为工薪阶层
You just joined the ranks of the employed.
算你狠 小嫩鸡
Kudos, fish.
你有种
You got spine.
好了 兄弟们 收工了
All right, cons! Break it down.
该走了  伙计们
Move it, guys.
我昨天看到维罗妮卡来了
Saw Veronica came by yesterday.
还和那个人定着婚吗
Still engaged to that guy?
是的
Yup.
本应该是和我(订婚)的
could have been me.
如果你没有自毁的话
If you hadn't self-destructed.
你认为我该和 莉莎・瑞克丝 分手
You think I meant to knock up Lisa Rix?
我只是一时麻木 受了打击
I was just being stupid. Hurt
不管怎么说都不应该放弃她的
Shouldn't have pushed her away, though.
你放弃了每个人
You pushed everyone away.
我是一个累赘
I'm an anchor.
我只会把她拖下水
All I'll do is drag'em down with me.
你为什么要雇他
Why did you hire him?
靠近你的朋友 更加靠近你的敌人
Keep your friends close,and your enemies closer.
你先前说的 当真吗
you mean what you said earlier?
我不是来度假的 相信我
I'm not here on vacation. Trust me.
逃出这里仅仅是个开始
Getting outside these walls is just the beginning.
还得需要钱
You're gonna need money.
我会有的
I'll have it.
并且外面还得有人
And people on the outside.
还得有人帮你隐姓埋名
People that can help you disappear.
我早就找好了
I've already got'em.
只是他们还不知道而已
They just don't know it yet.
听着 不管你要做什么 事先通知我
Look, whatever you've got going on, fill me in
我不想给蒙在鼓里
cos I'm in the dark here.
谢帕德公司 在99年得时候 拿到了改造这里的委托书
Chaparral Associates got the contract to retrofit this place in '99
四百万的合同 负责人无法胜任
$4 million.Head partner couldn't crack it
于是就把项目偷偷的 移交给了别人来做
so he subcontracted out an under-the-table sort of deal with a former associate.
那个人恰恰是我们公司的雇员
That guy was one of the partners in my firm.
我们也就顺便偷偷的修改了设计
We basically ghost-wrote the whole plan
偷工减料
crossed the "t's",dotted the "i's",grouted the tiles.
你看过结构蓝图
You've seen the blueprints.
不只看过而已
Better than that.
就在我的身上
I've got'em on me.
开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
我可什么都没看出来啊
Am I supposed to see something here?
看仔细点
Look closer.